# **SAMUEL RIVERA**

https://samuelriverac.com https://github.com/samuelriverac samuelrivera64@gmail.com

Tel: +584262029204

Self-driven and creative problem solver **FULL STACK DEVELOPER** with almost 3 years experience, planning, designing and developing scalable optimized beautiful and practical web apps and websites using PHP, Laravel, Wordpress, Node, Express, Vue or React, and other technologies depending on the company's tech stack. Now seeking a challenging and rewarding position in a Remote oriented Company.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Full Stack Web developer

Independant contractor / freelancer

Full-time (Remote Work)

May 2018 - Present

- Worked with more than 15 clients from different parts of the world with different scopes and requirements such as:
- Design and developing themes and plugins on Wordpress.
- Design, developing and implementing React single page applications.
- Consulting about Web marketing and Search engine optimization; and technical support.

## Frontend Developer

Orinoco.io

Full time (El Tigre, Anzoategui, Venezuela)

May 2018 - Oct 2018

- Designed a decentralized crypto exchange, along a small team of 3 and the 2 founders.
- Developed a Single Page Application with Vue, Vuetify, and GraphQL.
- After 3 months of finishing the Project, The user base doubled to 4000, and has made more than 75000 transactions in the same period.

# Full Stack Web Developer

PDVSA Petroleos de Venezuela S.A.

Internship (El Tigre, Anzoategui, Venezuela)

Feb 2018 – May 2018

- Made an analysis of the user stories told by 10 members of the Company's Administration management, and designed the application accordingly.
- Developed a web application on Codeigniter with Postgres as a database, according to the company's standards and methodologies, as explained by the software development team.
- Successfully implementated at the company's regional area of operations (Orinoco Oil Belt).

#### **PROJECTS**

**Personal Portfolio Website:** React, Gatsby and Sass (https://samuelriverac.com).

Unnamed Job board Project: React, Redux, Next, AdonisJS and MySQL.

### **SKILLS**

**Back-end Web development:** PHP, Codeigniter, Laravel, Wordpress, Woocommerce, Javascript, NodeJs, AdonisJs, ExpressJs, Python.

Front-end Web development: JQuery, React, Redux, NextJS, GatsbyJS, Vue, Vuex, NuxtJS

Databases: Mysql, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, GraphQL.

Web design: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Sass.

**Tools:** Git, Photoshop, Trello, Figma, Vultr, Insomnia, Slack.

Languages: Spanish (Native), English (Bilingual), Portuguese, Italian, French & German (Basic).

### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Systems Engineering**

National Polytechnical Experimental University of the Armed Forces (UNEFA).